Guide to the Henri Peyre Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henri Peyre letters
1929-1971
GEN MSS 309
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.2
(1 box)
Consists of letters to Peyre chiefly from French authors, plus one letter from Peyre to Donald Wing enclosing a typescript of Paul Claudel's "Partage de midi," which Peyre had made from the play at the Bibliotheque Nationale.
Peyre, Henri, 1901-1988
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Henri Peyre, 1941-1981.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
HENRI PEYRE
Henri Peyre was a member of the Yale University faculty for thirty-five years, and served as chair of the Department of French for twenty-five years.
Scope and Contents
The Henri Peyre Letters consist of letters to Peyre chiefly by French authors, plus one letter from Peyre to Donald Wing enclosing a typescript of Paul Claudel's "Partage de Midi," which Peyre had made from the copy of the play at the Bibliothèque Nationale de France. Some of the materials listed were previously cataloged separately.
Atkinson, Geoffroy, 1892-1960; Beauvoir, Simone de, 1908-1986; Bonnefoy, Yves, 1923-2016; Breton, André, 1896-1966; Camus, Albert, 1913-1960; Char, René, 1907-1988; Claudel, Paul, 1868-1955; Fontainas, André, 1865-1948; Giono, Jean, 1895-1970; Guillén, Jorge, 1893-1984; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Maritain, Jacques, 1882-1973; Maritain, Raïssa, 1883-1960; Marly, Anna, 1917-2006; Maurois, André, 1885-1967; Peyre, Henri, 1901-1988; Rolland, Romain, 1866-1944; Romains, Jules, 1885-1972; Saint-John Perse, 1887-1975; Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-1980; Schlumberger, Jean, 1877-1968; Ungaretti, Giuseppe, 1888-1970; Valéry, Paul, 1871-1945; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Wing, Donald Goddard, 1904-1972
- Letters, 1951 Dec 31; Series I
  - Atkinson, Geoffroy, 1951 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beauvoir, Simone de, n.y. Jul 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bonnefoy, Yves, 1963-67 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Breton, André, 1942-62 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Camus, Albert, 1946 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Char, René, 1963-71, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Claudel, Paul, 1933, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Box 1, folder 17
  - Etiemble, 1946 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fontainas, André, 1933 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Giono, Jean, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Guillén, Jorge, 1945-68 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hindemith, Paul, 1946 Nov 20 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Malraux, André, 1952-71 (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Maritain, Jacques, 1945-60 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Maritain, Raïssa, 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Marly, Anna, 1966 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Maurois, André, 1933, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Peyre, Henri to Donald Wing, Sterling Library, 1941 Dec 15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Scope and Contents
    With: typescript of Paul Claudel's "Partage de Midi." TLS from Peyre explains that Peyre had the typescript made from the play at the Bibliothèque Nationale.
  - Régnier, Henri de, [19]29 Jul 1 (Box 1, Folder 17a)
  - Rolland, Romain, 1936 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Romains, Jules, 1934 Mar 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Saint-John Perse, 1956-59 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sartre, Jean Paul, 1945, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Schlumberger, Jean, 1950 Aug 21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ungaretti, Giuseppe, 1960 Jul 19 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Valéry, Paul, 1929 Jun 18 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1952 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 25)